<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-03-25T11:13:31+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Chess Openings</title><subtitle>A website about various chess openings</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Adelaide Counter Gambit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/adelaide-counter-gambit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adelaide Counter Gambit" /><published>2025-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/adelaide-counter-gambit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/adelaide-counter-gambit.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.thechesswebsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/adelaide-counter-gambit.png" alt="Adelaide Counter Gambit" /></p>

<p>The Adelaide Counter Gambit is a solid attack against the King’s Gambit for black and begins with the moves:
1.e4 e5
2.f4 Nc6
3.Nf3 f5
When white plays the King’s Gambit they are usually looking to give up material and then have the initiative for the early part of the game. This defense turns the tables on white and gives black multiple attacking lines and control of the center. White has to be careful because if they don’t play properly there are many traps they can fall into. Below are different options they have after 3…f5.</p>

<h3 id="duckduckgo-results-about-adelaide-counter-gambit">Duckduckgo results about Adelaide Counter Gambit</h3>

<p>Before I start, I would like to give a brief introduction about this counter-gambit; The Adelaide Counter Gambit is a solid attack against the King’s Gambit for black and begins with the moves: 1.e4 e5 2.f4 Nc6 3.Nf3 f5</p>

<p>Video:<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ikFbzsTH6rc"><img src="https://tse2.mm.bing.net/th?id=OVP.Tsou8PVuJWvxRFdL7JFFigHgFo&amp;pid=Api" alt="" /></a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Albin Counter-Gambit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/albin-counter-gambit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Albin Counter-Gambit" /><published>2025-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/albin-counter-gambit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/albin-counter-gambit.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.thechesswebsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/albin2.jpg" alt="Albin Counter-Gambit" /></p>

<p>The Albin Counter-Gambit is a hyper aggressive defense for black against the ever so popular queens gambit from white.</p>
<ol>
  <li>d4 d5</li>
  <li>c4 e5
Black gives up his pawn on e5 so that his d pawn can be nicely placed on d4. This pawn is a huge thorn in the side of white and there are many trap that come from the Albin Counter-Gambit that white has to be on the lookout for. One of the most common traps in the Albin Counter-Gambit is the Lasker Trap which punishes white if he tries to attack the pawn on d4 with e3.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="duckduckgo-results-about-albin-counter-gambit">Duckduckgo results about Albin Counter-Gambit</h3>

<p>The Albin Countergambit is a chess opening that begins with the moves: . 1. d4 d5 2. c4 e5. and the usual continuation is: 3. dxe5 d4. The opening is a gambit and an uncommon response to the Queen’s Gambit.In exchange for the sacrificed pawn, Black has a central wedge at d4 and gets some chances for an attack.</p>

<p>Video:<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4TbXYs5bUDo"><img src="https://tse2.mm.bing.net/th?id=OVP.jn90Sgq7i2Hv_PdntX4EaAHgFo&amp;pid=Api" alt="" /></a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Alekhine Defense</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/alekhine-defense.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alekhine Defense" /><published>2025-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/alekhine-defense</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/alekhine-defense.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.thechesswebsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/alekhinedefensebig.jpg" alt="Alekhine Defense" /></p>

<ol>
  <li>e4 Nf6
Black looks to allow white to chase his knight all over the board with tempo gaining pawn moves that will control the center of the board. In exchange for the center control, black will look to undermine the overextended pawns from white.
The one thing black must always remember is that after his knight has been chased around he no longer can play passively and instead needs to attack the center that white has built up or he will be crushed by the pressure white can build up.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="duckduckgo-results-about-alekhine-defense">Duckduckgo results about Alekhine Defense</h3>

<p>Alexander Alekhine first played Alekhine’s Defense at Budapest in 1921, scoring a win and a draw, and continued playing it during the 1920s. Alekhine did not create the opening, and games from the 19th century that begin with 1.e4 Nf6 can be found, but his use popularized it. Alekhine. Photo: Wikimedia, public domain.</p>

<p>Video:<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=17ZbZaKsAuQ"><img src="https://tse3.mm.bing.net/th?id=OVF.8FvQ9FkKaRhfziCjxgjKgA&amp;pid=Api" alt="" /></a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Belgrade Gambit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/belgrade-gambit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Belgrade Gambit" /><published>2025-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/belgrade-gambit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/belgrade-gambit.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.thechesswebsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/belgrade-gambit.jpg" alt="Belgrade Gambit" /></p>

<p>The Belgrade Gambit is an aggressive line that derives from the Scotch Four Knights Game:</p>
<ol>
  <li>e4 e5</li>
  <li>Nf3 Nc6</li>
  <li>Nc3 Nf6</li>
  <li>d4 exd4</li>
  <li>Nd5
White’s most common move after 4…exd4 is to recapture with 5. Nxd4 but Nd5 allows white to transition into the Belgrade Gambit. As with many less known gambits, the Belgrade gets much of its advantage from your opponent not being familiar with how to play correctly as black. The good thing about this variation is that if you play 1. e4 2. Nf3 you’ll get many opportunities to try this out as it’s fairly easy to transition into a four knights game.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="duckduckgo-results-about-belgrade-gambit">Duckduckgo results about Belgrade Gambit</h3>

<p>The Belgrade Gambit. Join GM Williams as he teaches you this easy yet aggressive way to open the game, “the perfect opening for a lazy person.” 28 min 5 Challenges The Belgrade Gambit: Side Lines Simon Williams is back with another lesson on his secret weapon, the “spicy” Belgrade Gambit. Learn what to do if your opponent doesn’t stick to .</p>

<p>Video:<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1MKsjO6seBg"><img src="https://tse2.mm.bing.net/th?id=OVP.6NFnVnPr9mrQCjXc8R0DZgGgII&amp;pid=Api" alt="" /></a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Benoni Defense</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/benoni-defense.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Benoni Defense" /><published>2025-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/benoni-defense</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/benoni-defense.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.thechesswebsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/the-benoni-defense.jpg" alt="Benoni Defense" /></p>

<p>The Benoni Defense is a very aggressive line that black can play to counter the very common open by white d4. While many defenses against the queen pawn opening are closed and drawish, the Benoni Defense gives black many opportunities to not only equalize the position, but also to gain an advantage and play for the win.</p>
<ol>
  <li>d4 Nf6</li>
  <li>c4 c5</li>
  <li>d5
In the Modern Benoni Defense, the main focus of the game is white’s center control of the light squares with its key pawn on d5 and black’s control of the center from the dark squares. Black will usually fianchetto his bishop on the kingside to g7 to add extra support to the dark squares.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="duckduckgo-results-about-benoni-defense">Duckduckgo results about Benoni Defense</h3>

<p>The Benoni Defense, or simply the Benoni, is a chess opening characterized by an early reply of …c5 against White’s opening move 1.d4.. The original form of the Benoni, now known as the Old Benoni, is characterized by . 1. d4 c5. This leaves Black a few options such as an early …f5 and an early dark-squared bishop trade by …Be7-g5, but has the drawback that White is no longer committed .</p>

<p>Video:<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N8mNUgzFD0s"><img src="https://tse1.mm.bing.net/th?id=OVP.dKKb0nSi-dUxv4MS0q6D3wHgFo&amp;pid=Api" alt="" /></a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bird’s Opening</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/bird-s-opening.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bird’s Opening" /><published>2025-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/bird%E2%80%99s-opening</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/bird-s-opening.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.thechesswebsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/the-birds-opening.jpg" alt="Bird’s Opening" /></p>

<p>The Bird’s Opening is the 6th most popular opening and is a very aggressive opening. White starts out weakening his king side and starts a flank attack on the center with his f pawn. This opening is not used in lots of top level play but some of the most beautiful games in chess history have been played using the Bird’s Opening.</p>
<ol>
  <li>f4
After black defends with d5 the game will transpose into a reverse of the Dutch defense, where white opens with d4 and black responds with f5. White’s main focus is on the dark squares in the game which is a big difference than the usual light squares that white usually focuses on.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="duckduckgo-results-about-birds-opening">Duckduckgo results about Bird’s Opening</h3>

<p>Bird’s Opening (or the Dutch Attack) is a chess opening characterised by the move: 1. f4. Named after 19th century English player Henry Bird, Bird’s opening is a standard flank opening. White’s strategic ideas involve control of the e5-square, offering good attacking chances at the expense of slightly weakening their own kingside. Black may .</p>

<p>Video:<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J5qNc20njV4"><img src="https://tse1.mm.bing.net/th?id=OVP.acgAsMO7PXQ06XCG39BMTgHgFo&amp;pid=Api" alt="" /></a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bishop’s Opening</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/bishop-s-opening.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bishop’s Opening" /><published>2025-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/bishop%E2%80%99s-opening</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/bishop-s-opening.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.thechesswebsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/bishops-chess-opening.png" alt="Bishop’s Opening" /></p>

<p>The Bishop’s Opening is one of the oldest openings in chess but has fallen out of favor recently. It starts with the moves:</p>
<ol>
  <li>e4 e5</li>
  <li>Bc4
White decides to develop the light square bishop before bringing the knight to f3. The three main responses from black are 2…Nf6, 2…Nc6, and 2…Bc5. White has good chances against each of these lines and can fall into more popular opening variations if they choose.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="duckduckgo-results-about-bishops-opening">Duckduckgo results about Bishop’s Opening</h3>

<p>The Bishop’s Opening is a chess opening that begins with the moves: 1. e4 e5 2. Bc4 White attacks Black’s f7-square and prevents Black from advancing the d-pawn to d5. By ignoring the beginner’s maxim “develop knights before bishops “, White leaves their f-pawn unblocked, preserving the possibility of f2-f4.</p>

<p>Video:<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qb3PWiIbIJs"><img src="https://tse1.mm.bing.net/th?id=OVP.wwloTtBU9ilMVY1UU7fvFgHgFo&amp;pid=Api" alt="" /></a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Blackmar-Diemer Gambit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/blackmar-diemer-gambit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blackmar-Diemer Gambit" /><published>2025-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/blackmar-diemer-gambit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/blackmar-diemer-gambit.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.thechesswebsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/blackmar_big.jpg" alt="Blackmar-Diemer Gambit" /></p>

<p>The Blackmar-Diemer Gambit is one of the most ambitious attempts for white to gain a developmental advantage.</p>
<ol>
  <li>d4 d5</li>
  <li>e4 dxe4</li>
  <li>Nc3
From the second move white looks to give away his king’s pawn. Although many top GM’s find this to be unsound, many club level players have great success with it and if you are a very aggressive player I recommend playing it from time to time.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="duckduckgo-results-about-blackmar-diemer-gambit">Duckduckgo results about Blackmar-Diemer Gambit</h3>

<p>The Blackmar-Diemer Gambit (or BDG) is a chess opening characterized by the moves: . 1. d4 d5 2. e4 dxe4 3. Nc3. where White intends to follow up with f3, usually on the fourth move. White obtains a tempo and a half-open f-file in return for a pawn, and as with most gambits, White aims to achieve rapid development and active posting of their pieces in order to rapidly build up an attack at .</p>

<p>Video:<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mxtUxgupAHY"><img src="https://tse1.mm.bing.net/th?id=OVP.35mF4-fu3sBVDrRlpWLjRgHgFo&amp;pid=Api" alt="" /></a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bogo Indian Defense</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/bogo-indian-defense.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bogo Indian Defense" /><published>2025-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/bogo-indian-defense</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/bogo-indian-defense.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.thechesswebsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/bogo-indian-defense.png" alt="Bogo Indian Defense" /></p>

<p>The Bogo Indian Defense is a chess opening that arrives after the starting moves:</p>
<ol>
  <li>d4 Nf6</li>
  <li>c4 e6</li>
  <li>Nf3 Bb4+
Many players with the white pieces will choose the third move Nf3 instead of Nc3 because they want to avoid the Nimzo Indian Defense. Black has multiple options after Nf3 but Bb4+ is a common move seen at all levels of play.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="duckduckgo-results-about-bogo-indian-defense">Duckduckgo results about Bogo Indian Defense</h3>

<p>The Bogo-Indian Defence is named after the Russian-born German master Efim Bogoljubow who is believed to have originated the opening and played it regularly in the 1920s. Subsequent prominent players to have adopted the Bogo-Indian include Aron Nimzowitsch, Paul Keres, Tigran Petrosian, Bent Larsen, Vasily Smyslov, Viktor Korchnoi, Ulf Andersson, Michael Adams and Nikita Vitiugov.</p>

<p>Video:<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3HqUziP4nhE"><img src="https://tse1.mm.bing.net/th?id=OVP.qDjf0wUZa0gksBRrFaVpXwHgFo&amp;pid=Api" alt="" /></a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Budapest Gambit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/budapest-gambit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Budapest Gambit" /><published>2025-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-03-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/budapest-gambit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2025/03/24/budapest-gambit.html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.thechesswebsite.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/budapest_big.jpg" alt="Budapest Gambit" /></p>

<p>The Budapest Gambit is one of the least common gambits but still offers black a lot of interesting play. In the main line for example, white can easily fall into a trap that ends in checkmate very early in the game.</p>
<ol>
  <li>d4 Nf6</li>
  <li>c4 e5
In the second move, black looks to give up his pawn on e5 but then starts to develop of his pieces to add pressure on the e5 pawn. White will be unable to hold onto the extra pawn and therefore many times will just give back the pawn and continue to develop pieces and not worry about the pawn advantage.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="duckduckgo-results-about-budapest-gambit">Duckduckgo results about Budapest Gambit</h3>

<p>Learn about the Budapest Gambit, a tricky opening for Black that offers a pawn and attacks White’s knight. Explore its variations, history, and key ideas with lessons and challenges.</p>

<p>Video:<br />
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=urITvqQleUE"><img src="https://tse2.mm.bing.net/th?id=OVP.qqVwMfjLSuN_wtvx8ScMNQHgFo&amp;pid=Api" alt="" /></a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>